MIRANDA KNEE

WEB DEVELOPER/DESIGNER

Detailed orientated problem solver with a strong passion for responsive web design and development. Continuously strives to be up-to-date on the latest web technologies through research and participating in local events. Provides a strong work ethic and always willing to learn and enhance skills set.

SKILLS AND EXPERTISE

Specialties:

- Development
- Design
- Debugging
- WordPress
- Google Analytics
- Bootstrap
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Print Design
- MailChimp
- Kirby
- Photography

Tech Specialties:

- HTML5
- CSS3
- PHP
- JavaScript
- ¡Query
- Git
- Terminal
- Node.js
- Atom
- Visual Studio Code

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Creation of custom WordPress themes and functionality based on user(s) needs.
- Recreation of company Squarespace sites to save annual costs.

EXPERIENCE

Allegheny Conference, Pittsburgh PA

October 2015 - Present

Web Developer

Responsibly for the backend development, hosting and maintenance of websites and company intranet. Registers and renews domain names and website hosting. Designs SEO best practices. Assists with designing graphics for use on websites and/or social media. Photography for events and for use on websites.

Heartland ECSI, Coraopolis PA

June 2014 - October 2015

Graphic Design Manager

Work closely with marketing, sales, product development and business leaders to provide support for creation of visual imagery for multiple documents and website needs. Develop graphics design that effectively communicates the ideas being promoted by the collateral pieces.

Precise, Inc., Pittsburgh PA

January 2012 - June 2013

Production Artist

Record standard and interactive depositions according to industry standards. Assist in the creation of visual aids through use of PowerPoint, Photoshop and/or Illustrator. Capture, produce, and edit day-in-the-life, on-site, and other litigation related videos.

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Pittsburgh Technical College

June 2016 - July 2017

Freelance Web Developer

Work with in-house web developer to prep new website for launch and reveal of Pittsburgh Technical Institute's transitions to Pittsburgh Technical College through image collection and optimization as well as UI/UX consulting.

Pittsburgh GiveCamp

October 2014 & 2017

Volunteer Web Developer

Participated in GiveCamp 2014 & 2017 and played an acting role as a web designer/developer for a nonprofit organization, PCRG, an organization for economic justice for communities throughout Allegheny County, Pennsylvania and Kiva Pittsburgh a n organization that assists small businesses financially. Each time at GiveCamp I worked with a team of volunteers to help these nonprofits redesign and enhance their website needs by using WordPress themes and plugins that could be easily maintained and cost effective.

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Creating custom child theme for client's WordPress site to update homepage design while maintaining previous theme branding and functions.
- 1st place for Web Interactive and Development portfolio show, 2015.
- Judge for Pittsburgh Technical Institute Multimedia, Video portfolio show 2013.

EDUCATION

Pittsburgh Technical Institute, Oakdale, PA

Associate in Science Degree, Multimedia Technologies Concentration in Web Interactive/Development GPA: 3.9

Associate in Science Degree, Multimedia Technologies Concentration in Video/3-Dimensional Design GPA: 3.94 2014 - 2015

2007 - 2009